Adnan Hyder Pervez (MSCS)



Availability: Immediately

Contact

Address:

Shabia ME10 Musaffag Abu Dhabi UAE/ Near Macdonld FSD PAK

Phone:

+92 300 7658545

Email:

12345adnan@gmail.com

Skype: adnanhyderfsd Date of birth: 1-10-1991 Nationality: Pakistani

Passport Number: EH6172802 Passport Expiry :30 SEP 2024

Languages

English Urdu Hindi Punjabi

Hobbies

Driving Playing Games, Table Tennis

Summary

Senior resources for Office management & software products, handling queries about Web Development specializing in development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, PHP OOP, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL. Strong background in project management and customer relations.

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- WordPress, Codeigniter
- Bootstrap, ReactJs, VueJs
- Mysql , , JSON , SQL
- Ecommerce ,
 Woocommerce

- Creative design
- HTML, CSS
- JS, PHP
- Laravel, Cake Php
- Core PHP
- Adobe Scripting
- AJAX , backend APIS

Experience

Web Developer (Laravel, Codeigniter, PHP) - 01/2018 to 02/2020 Volgo Int pvt , Lahore

- Cooperate Ecommerce team with designers to create clean interfaces, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Working with the sales team to identify new queries
- Develop project concepts, functionality and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with other developers to manage large, complex design for corporate clients.

WordPress Developer(PHP,WP,JS)- 04/2016 to 01/2018 Techopialabs, Lahore

- Giving support at WordPress theme. (Creation, Bugs, update)
- Develop New functionality for Themes & Plugins.
- Maintaining new Queries from clients and for order estimations.
- Maintain the quality of WordPress themes at ThemForest.
- Track users request, comment, and complaints.
- Online troubleshooting of static and dynamic code.
- Maintain the rating at Envato markets ThemeForest.

Web Designer & Developer (WP, HTML, CSS, JS)- 02/2014 to 03/20160

EzSolutions, Faisalabad

 Marketing of products digitally, PSD, Icons, Logos, banners, PSD to HTML, PSD to Wordpress, Complete Front end Solution

Junior Web Developer (HTML, CSS, JS)- 05/2012 to 01/2014

Rise Innovation, Faisalabad

- PSD to HTML, PSD to WordPress,
- Complete Front end developer

Education

Masters of Science in **Computer Science** -2018 **University of Agriculture**, PK

Masters in **Computer Science** -2015 **NCBA&E**, PK

Bachelors in **Computer Science** - 2012 **Virtual University of Pakistan**, PK

Certifications & Skills

Courses:

SEO, Digital Marketing, Graphic Designing, English Proficiency,

Programming Languages:

JavaScript, HTML5, PHP OOP, CSS, SQL, MySQL.

Graphic Design software's:

Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop.

Project Management Tools:

GIT, SVN, Composers, Trello, Jira, Asana, Bitbucket, Microsoft Visio, WHM, Cpanel, Hpanel, Hosting, Staging Domain,

Extra information

- Cleared International Kangaroo Math 2007
- Best Football Player State level School 2008
- Educational Expo 2014
- WorldCamp 2018

Portfolio

- 1. https://wordpress.org/plugins/techopialabs-backups/ (WordPress Officail Plugin)
- 2. http://Helpyea.com (Laravel)
- 3. https://www.volgopoint.com/b2bclassified/ (Codigniter)
- 4. https://rentmycar.pk/ (RestApi , Codigniter)
- 5. https://www.iconichotel.com.my (WordPress)
- 6. http://demo.helpyea.com/maidaclassified/ (Bootstrap, HTML)
- 7. http://demo.helpyea.com/maidasoftwareservice/ (Jquery , HTML)
- 8. http://demo.helpyea.com/joba/html/ (Vue Js, HTML)
- 9. https://stoneridgehomes.co.uk/ (WordPress)
- 10. https://www.zaxnetworks.com/ (woocommerce Ecommerce)
- 11. http://demo.helpyea.com/portfolio/ Complete Portfolio

Social Profiles

<u>WordPress Plugin</u> <u>Linkdin</u> <u>GitHub</u> <u>Stackoverflow</u> <u>Personalblog</u>